+972-58-468-1836
Shahar.spencer@mail.huji.ac.il
http://www.linkedin.com/in/
shahar-spencer

Skills & Interests

Machine Learning NLP spaCy NLP library Numpy & Pandas Data Analysis Python C&C++ R Github React & Node.js

Courses

93 in Infinitesimal Calculus I 99 in Probability and Statistics 90 in Data Structures 94 in Linear Algebra I 88 in C&C++

Projects

Tool to automatically recognize creative natural language Machine Learning Library scikit-learn Participant at HUJI hackathon

Awards

Young Scientists and Developers Contest Young Historians Contest

Languages Native English Native Hebrew

Shahar Spencer

Completing my BSc studies in Computer Science. I have a passion for research, Natural Language Processing and Machine Learning. Engaged in NLP & ML project as the main programmer in Python in a multidisciplinary research group. Team player with great communication and research skills and a creative problem-solver. Native English speaker. Pursuing advanced NLP & ML coursework.

Education

BSc in Computer Science and Cognitive Science, Hebrew University, Jerusalem, 2020 - present

- GPA 88
- Implemented Python Machine Learning Library Scikit-learn, 2022
 - Developed classes and explored various applications within the library as part of course project

The Israeli Arts and Science Academy for Gifted Students, Jerusalem, Israel, 2014 - 2017

- Young Scientists and Developers Contest Prize Winner, 2017
- Israeli History Society's "Young Historians" Contest Prize Winner, 2017
- High School graduation with honors
- Completed 5 units: Math, English, Physics, Latin

Work Experience

Research Assistant and programmer, HUJI NLP lab, 2022 - present

- Led as the head programmer for an NLP & ML project, collaborating with a team of researchers
- Conducted research using Python and ML & Data Science libraries to automatically identify creative occurrences in Natural Language
- Demonstrated motivation, teamwork and self-learning capabilities
- Employed creative technical solutions to challenges that arise in the project, including developing Streamlit annotation interface

Army Service

Shooting Instructor, 2017 - 2019

- Instructed weapons training for Infantry Units
- Promoted to commander, leading a course for 40 soldiers designated to instruct Infantry Units